# **Peter Safwat**

Software Engineer

 Birth
 March 23, 1998

 Address
 Imbaba, Giza

 Phone
 0120 6284 377

Mail p.pator@outlook.com Github github.com/peter44322 LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/peterzacch

# **SUMMARY**

I'm +3 years experience Software Engineer, I start coding when I was 13, programming is more than a job for me it is a hobby. I'm a self-motivated, creative, problem-solver, and determined Engineer. my objective is to contribute more to the open-source community.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer

2018-present

Bee Interactives., Full-time

- Developing and directing software system validation and testing methods.
- Analyzing data to effectively coordinate the installation of new systems or the modification of existing systems.
- Managing the software development lifecycle.
- Developing and executing project plans.
- Applying mathematics and statistics to problem-solving initiatives.
- Applying best practices and standard operating procedures.

# **Backend Developer**

2017-2018

Egyadv., Full-time

- Main focus on coding and debugging
- Build high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future
- Develop functional and sustainable web applications with clean codes
- Define and communicate technical and design requirements
- Collaborate with Front-end developers

# **Programming Instructor**

2017-2018

Pharaonic Technology Systems., Part-time

- Provide hands-on instruction and practical training in Java, Python, and Arduino.
- Teach courses from beginner level to advance.
- Create instructional materials

# **EDUCATION**

### BCS. Faculty of computer and artificial intelligence

2016-2020

Cairo University

Major - Computer science

Minor - Information systems

# **SKILLS**

Languages Arabic (mother tongue)

English (professional)

Programming Languages

PYTHON, JAVASCRIPT, C#, C++, PHP, JAVA

Databases MySql, postgresql, mongodb, Redis

Frameworks Laravel, Reactjs, Angular, Django, express, Ruby on Rails

# **PROJECTS**

#### World Youth Forum

A System that helped the WYF organizers filter and validate all the candidates for the Forum, with a very large database operation we overcome many performance challenges

## Orange sonetelhaya

A Video Generator, I Worked in this project as a full-stack,

- creating the frontend using react
- in order to preview the video in a short time we used Lottie.js.
- and we recorded the video using node.js, puppeteer, and FFmpeg.
- we used WebSockets to give realtime feedback to the user.

#### Bznsbuilder

Worked in frontend

#### Dijkstra Visualization

An Interactive Dijkstra Algorithm Visualization tool using react and vis.js. visualize the solution of max flow problem and shortest path

## Picks courier

picks courier is a start-up based in Cairo, Egypt. it offers delivery solutions to individuals, SMEs, and corporates. We own and manage a highly professional courier network through an innovative business model.

### Game Ai

An Ai For a searching game it uses prolog to make a tree of the game states, it also has an interactive UI for setting the initial state of the game and show the solution.

#### C Lexical Analyzer

Python Lexical Analyzer for c syntax. it uses the magic of regex to identify the syntax and categorize them.

#### Music Player

Web Music Player Using nextjs and Napster Apis.

## KingsMen

An Express.js Cloths shop Web app with MongoDB database

### Vector quantization

Java Implementation for the Vector quantization Compress Algorithm.

## Fuzzy ToolBox

Fuzzy Logic Implementation in Python with a graph plotter

## Adaptive huffman coding

Java Implementation for Adaptive Huffman Compression Algorithm.

#### smooth curve fitting

Python genetic algorithm used to fit a curve giving some points and graph them.

# Knapsack genetic algorithm

Solving the Knapsack problem using genatic algorithm.

#### Tic tac toe Game

Reactjs Tic Tac Toe Game

## Calculating pi by collisions

A Visualization for calculating the digits of pi using elastic collisions between two objects of different masses and a wall. Let me explain with this diagram.

## CryptoMail

Secure nodejs Mail server implemented using blockchain with peer to peer architecture.

# **OPEN SOURCE PACKAGES**

### **DyForm**

An Open source Laravel package to help create dynamic forms with high-performance insert and retrieve operations.

### Completeness Checker

An Open source Laravel package to help track the completeness of an entity, it calculate how many fields the user has filled and it generates a percentage of completeness.

# Swaggerator

An Open source Laravel package to help Developers document their APIS With a bunch of easy commands.

### **JoQueryGenerator**

An open-source laravel package to help optimizing data tables query. with the help of the Clovis addon it joins table conditionally.

#### **Html Extractor**

Nodejs tool for extracting html ,js ,css files from a giving url

#### Vast Converter

Converter for converting vast xml files version 1 to vast version 2

# **BOOKS & COURSES**

The Nature of Code - Daniel Shiffman

Head First Design Patterns - Elisabeth Freeman and Kathy Sierra

CS50's Introduction to Computer Science - Harvard

Good Parts of JavaScript and the Web - Douglas Crockford

THE ODIN PROJECT Web Development - Udacity

# **PUBLICATION**

• Laravel dynamic databases - Medium Article

# LIFE PHILOSOPHY

however difficult life may seem, there is always something you can do, and succeed at. It matters that you don't just give up - Stephen Hawking

# **REFERENCES**

Available upon request